I'm Dr. Andy Galpin,
I'm a professor of kinesiology
in the Center for Sport
Performance at Cal State Fullerton.
In that center,
our mission is to conduct
and disseminate research
that enhances human performance.
In addition to my role
as a scientist there,
I've also worked directly
with professional athletes
for nearly 20 years,
I've been fortunate to work
with a number of high profile
and highly successful individuals.
This would include: Olympic
gold and silver medalists,
world champions, MVPs,
Cy Young Winners, Hall of Famers,
and more, across a variety of sports.
But not only have I had a passion
for conducting human performance research
and applying it to real
athletes in the field,
I've also made a career emphasis
to get that information out to the public.
So in an effort to continue that,
and at the strong encouragement of Andrew
as well as the rest of the team here
at the Huberman Lab
podcast and many others,
I'm extremely excited to
be launching my own show.
My main focus of this show
is not necessarily physiology
that is healthy, or really healthy.
It's what is maximally healthy.
How do I optimize and peak
my physical performance?
Now, I'm fully aware
most of you listening,
and in fact, honestly myself as well,
have really no interest
in breaking world records
in any physical feats, now
or anytime in the future.
And so you may be asking yourself,
"Why would this information matter to me?"
Well think about it this way.
If we understand the
tools and tactics required
to perform at this kind of a level,
when dialed up to 10 in the
most extreme environments,
that's going to help us
understand what to do
when the dial's only at five or six.
Along the way, I'm going to
share with you all of my secrets.
Well, maybe not all of them.
But the things that we use
that you're not going to necessarily find
in the peer-reviewed research.
While doing that, I'm going to
be sharing with you candidly
some advanced tools,
technologies, and tactics
that may not be within your budget,
or even frankly available
to the general public.
So at the same time, I
will go out of my way
to ensure I mention alternatives,
so what strategies are available,
ideally low or free cost,
that are still scientifically valid ways
to either identify,
interpret, or intervene,
and drive the appropriate
physiological change
that you're looking for.
So admittedly, while we're
going to be sticking mostly
to the peer-reviewed science,
I will from time to time
enter in my personal opinion
from my coaching practice,
and I will be sure I'm clarifying you
when it is my opinion,
versus what is the scientific consensus.
With that all being said, I'm
incredibly excited and proud
to release to you this first season.
I want to keep the content as
high of quality as possible.
So this first season is going to only be
about a dozen or so episodes.
After that, we're going to take some time
to go back to the lab,
work on some more stuff,
and only come back for season two
once we've achieved that
same level of excellence
we hope we've accomplished in season one.
I sincerely thank you for your
time and attention thus far,
and hope to see you back
here for episode one.